Maximiliano Fernando Escobar Viegas

Date of birth: 16/08/1995 | **Nationality:** Portuguese, Chilean | **Phone number:** (+49) 17668927290 (Mobile) |

Email address: maxescovi@gmail.com | **Website:** https://elmaxiboy.github.io/resume/ | **YouTube:**

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzgOgt27CN7sE6LqK-bA89w

Address: Dachauerstrasse 245, Apt 307, 80637, München, Germany (Home)

ABOUT ME

I am an industrial engineer and a Master of Science student specializing in Energy Markets, with a major in Computer Engineering. I always push myself into learning new things. I have a strong interest for sustainability and I am passionate about integrating digital platforms to enhance business processes and create value. In my free time, I love hanging out in the mountains and making music with friends.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/10/2023 - CURRENT München, Germany

WORKING STUDENT SIEMENS

Support in the configuration of demonstration systems for Perception applications based on the Siemens Industrial Edge infrastructure. This includes the configuration and installation of systems on peripheral devices and associated applications as well as the adaptation and further development of the applications, e.g. in the area of data and result visualization in graphical user interfaces.

27/12/2020 - 31/12/2023 Santiago, Chile

AUTOMATION CONSULTANT PRACTIA GLOBAL

Implementing software automation solutions for the retail industry, aiming to enhance it's daily working process, by means of reducing manual labor and optimizing operational costs. This is achieved by a series of tasks, which consists of scouting business processes with high automation potential, designing, developing and implementing the solutions. Combining different tools and frameworks if needed. Collecting data for visualization and monitoring of the business's performance via interactive dashboards.

29/10/2018 - 28/11/2020 Santiago, Chile

RPA CONSULTANT SISUA DIGITAL

Implementing software automation solutions for different clients in the energy, retail and scientific research market in order to lower operational costs and efficiently assign productive resources. The main responsability was developing RPA (robotic process automation) bots, structuring the business data involved in the process and building BI dashboards for keeping track of several business metrics.

30/11/2017 - 27/02/2018 Santiago, Chile

QUALITY ASSURANCE INTERN SONDA

Testing and verifying the correct execution of the features programmed in the context of enhancing the payment system of the public transport in Santiago using contactless smart cards.

29/06/2016 - 28/11/2017 Santiago, Chile

ENTREPRENEUR LEADER APRENDO EMPRENDO

Visiting highschools in the Metropolitan Region of Chile with the mission of encouraging young students to take part of an entrepreneurial school contest. Giving talks about different personal entrepreneuring experiences and the key aspects of the process. At the end of the contest, finals were carried out with the students that presented the most outstanding ideas, hence effective communication workshops were implemented for them.

26/02/2015 - 28/12/2017 Santiago, Chile

PROJECT MANAGER UNIVERSIDAD DE CHILE

Leading an engineering students' team in the developing of a mobile application for reporting crime and incidents within the area of the university campus. The app was successfully implemented during one semester and obtained the first prize in the "Safe City" tech challenge organized by Sonda in 2016. Link to the article in a local newspaper.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/10/2023 - CURRENT München, Germany

M. SC. MANAGEMENT AND TECHNOLOGY Technische Universität München

Address Arcisstr. 21, 80333, München, Germany

Website https://www.tum.de/studium/studienangebot/detail/management-and-technology-tum-bwl-master-of-science-msc

Field of study Energy Markets, Computer Engineering

28/02/2014 - 22/12/2020 Santiago, Chile

INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER Universidad de Chile

Address Beauchef 850, 837-0456, Santiago, Chile | Website https://www.dii.uchile.cl/

30/01/2016 - 28/06/2016 València, Spain

BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION INTERNATIONAL STUDENT Universitat Politècnica de València

Address Camí de Vera , 46022, València, Spain | Website http://www.upv.es/es

30/10/2016 - 13/11/2016 Santa Clara, United States

RESOLVE LEARNING PROGRAM'S ATTENDEE Singularity University

Address 2831 Mission College Blvd, 95054, Santa Clara, United States | Website https://www.su.org/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **SPANISH**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	C1	C1	B2	C1	B2
GERMAN	A2	A2	A2	A2	A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Programming skills

Docker | Java | Python | C# | SQL | JavaScript | Rust | HTML | .NET | R | Git | Experience in the Kubernetes with Azure cloud | Graph API | Object-Oriented Programming | MVC | PowerBI | Mixed-Integer Linear Programming | API | RPA | ETL | Agile (Scrum)

Audiovisual production

Sony Vegas | Reason Studios